<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Defs>
    <VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
        <defName>VPE_Empath</defName>
        <label>empath</label>
        <description>Empath psycasts are focused on enhancing the mood of others, one way or another.</description>
        <background>UI/Backgrounds/EmpathPath</background>
        <altBackground>UI/AlternativeBackgrounds/PathBG_Empath</altBackground>
        <tab>Psycasts</tab>
        <tooltip>Empaths are psycasters committed to serving their community and boosting their kin’s spirits. Known to inspire joy with but a few words, as well as snap people out of mental states, particularly powerful empaths can emit strong psychic soothes or even skip blood-related family members from across the globe.</tooltip>
    </VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
    <VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
      <defName>VPE_Skipmaster</defName>
      <label>skipmaster</label>
      <description>Skipmaster psycasts are focused on using skipgates to change the course of battle or the life of the colony.</description>
      <background>UI/Backgrounds/SkipmasterPath</background>
      <altBackground>UI/AlternativeBackgrounds/PathBG_Skipmaster</altBackground>
      <tab>Psycasts</tab>
      <tooltip>Skipmasters often served the Empire by establishing convoluted skipdoor networks. Masters of logistics and bending space, they can skip people to desired locations and can even use skipgates for everyday chores - such as creating solar pinholes or skipping water to extinguish flames.</tooltip>
    </VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
    <VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
      <defName>VPE_Conflagrator</defName>
      <label>conflagrator</label>
      <description>Conflagrator path is focused on manipulating fire, heat and energy to eliminate enemies.</description>
      <background>UI/Backgrounds/ConflagratorPath</background>
      <altBackground>UI/AlternativeBackgrounds/PathBG_Conflagrator</altBackground>
      <tab>Psycasts</tab>
      <tooltip>Conflagrators are the masters of flame, capable of eradicating entire regiments of enemy infantry using powerful fire tornadoes and explosions. Greatly respected across all psycaster paths, conflagrators bring fear, death and the stench of burnt meat wherever they go.</tooltip>
    </VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
    <VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
      <defName>VPE_Protector</defName>
      <label>protector</label>
      <description>Protector path is focused on providing aid and protection to your pawns, stopping them from dying and allowing you to escape from dangerous situations unscratched.</description>
      <background>UI/Backgrounds/ProtectorPath</background>
      <altBackground>UI/AlternativeBackgrounds/PathBG_Protector</altBackground>
      <tab>Psycasts</tab>
      <tooltip>Protectors serve on the front lines, defending the brave soldiers from harm. Not only can they stop projectiles using powerful skipshields, but they can also help the body recover from wounds, as well as boost the natural regeneration and immunity of those in need.</tooltip>
    </VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
    <VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
      <defName>VPE_Warlord</defName>
      <label>warlord</label>
      <description>Warlord path is focused on upgrading the warfare capabilities of the Psycaster and psycaster alone - as all the Warlord psycasts are to an extent self-cast.</description>
      <background>UI/Backgrounds/WarlordPath</background>
      <altBackground>UI/AlternativeBackgrounds/PathBG_Warlord</altBackground>
      <tab>Psycasts</tab>
      <tooltip>Masters of warfare, warlords serve only themselves, able to improve their perception, reflexes, speed and stamina at will. Feared anywhere they go, a powerful warlord will never miss a shot and their blade will always find its target.</tooltip>
    </VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
    <VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
      <defName>VPE_Chronopath</defName>
      <label>chronopath</label>
      <description>Chronopath path is focused on manipulating time, making things older, completing growth of plants, or de-aging your pawns.</description>
      <background>UI/Backgrounds/ChronopathPath</background>
      <altBackground>UI/AlternativeBackgrounds/PathBG_Chronopath</altBackground>
      <tab>Psycasts</tab>
      <tooltip>Chronopaths are rare and mysterious psycasters, capable of manipulating the fabric of time itself. By creating skipgates through time rather than space, chronopaths can have weapons assemble themselves, alter someone’s age at will, and even create bizarre timequakes that accelerate the time of everything around them by dozens of years.</tooltip>
    </VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
    <VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
      <defName>VPE_Archotechist</defName>
      <label>archotechist</label>
      <description>Archotechist path is a special path locked only for Empire-based psycasters. It allows spreading insanity, using psychic shock to down any wrong-doers, and to offload neural heat to others, as well as use neural heat in combat.</description>
      <background>UI/Backgrounds/ArchotechistPath</background>
      <altBackground>UI/AlternativeBackgrounds/PathBG_Archotechist</altBackground>
      <tab>Psycasts</tab>
      <tooltip>A path so mysterious only imperial scholars can confirm rumours, archotechists are able to tap into archotech engines and exert power so ridiculous and bizarre that it really makes one question their sanity. Archotechists can simply drive entire armies to insanity, and can even manipulate neural heat to mutilate their adversaries.</tooltip>
      <lockedReason>Imperials only</lockedReason>
      <requiredBackstoriesAny>
        <li>
          <categoryName>ImperialFighter</categoryName>
          <slot>Childhood</slot>
        </li>
        <li>
          <categoryName>ImperialFighter</categoryName>
          <slot>Adulthood</slot>
        </li>
        <li>
          <categoryName>ImperialRoyal</categoryName>
          <slot>Childhood</slot>
        </li>
        <li>
          <categoryName>ImperialRoyal</categoryName>
          <slot>Adulthood</slot>
        </li>
      </requiredBackstoriesAny>
    </VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
    <VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
      <defName>VPE_Necropath</defName>
      <label>necropath</label>
      <description>Necropath is a path focused on distributing fear and death, whilst also gaining from death and corpses. You can resurrect fallen allies, prohibit them from dying and raise hordes of skeletons to fight for your cause.</description>
      <background>UI/Backgrounds/NecropathPath</background>
      <altBackground>UI/AlternativeBackgrounds/PathBG_Necropath</altBackground>
      <tab>Psycasts</tab>
      <tooltip>Masters of the dark arts, necropaths live to defy death itself. They can cast fear into the hearts of their enemies, emit a paralytic pulse to knock attackers down, rot away the flesh of living bodies and ultimately summon the dead - either through wicked enthrallment or sacred resurrection.</tooltip>
    </VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
    <VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
      <defName>VPE_Staticlord</defName>
      <label>staticlord</label>
      <description>Staticlord is a path focused on blasting enemies with electricity, disabling electronics and controlling the storm itself.</description>
      <background>UI/Backgrounds/StaticlordPath</background>
      <altBackground>UI/AlternativeBackgrounds/PathBG_Staticlord</altBackground>
      <tab>Psycasts</tab>
      <tooltip>Lords of thunder and lightning, staticlords are excellent psycasters when it comes to controlling the flow of electricity and fighting against mechanoid swarms. They can summon powerful lightning bolts in many shapes and forms, as well as manipulate the weather to generate localised lightning storms and hurricanes.</tooltip>
    </VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
    <VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
      <defName>VPE_Archon</defName>
      <label>archon</label>
      <description>Archon path is the path of a psychic leader, providing various buffs to the entire colony, but also ruling with an iron fist. It’s also a path that allows you to drain enemy psycasters and gain Psycast levels this way.</description>
      <background>UI/Backgrounds/ArchonPath</background>
      <altBackground>UI/AlternativeBackgrounds/PathBG_Archon</altBackground>
      <tab>Psycasts</tab>
      <tooltip>The path of kings, archons often occupy the highest seats in their local governments. Being able to easily bond with others, manipulate their enemies either through friendship or pain, with powerful archons strengthening themselves by draining the psyessence of other psycasters.</tooltip>
    </VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
    <VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
      <defName>VPE_Frostshaper</defName>
      <label>frostshaper</label>
      <description>Frostshaper is a path about manipulating the elements, particularly the cold, to your advantage. Not only you get to use the cold to freeze and slow enemies, frostshapers also gain access to many utility psycasts that either construct shelters out of ice blocks, or create cooling crystals that can be used both as a temporary fridge, and a trap.</description>
      <background>UI/Backgrounds/FrostshaperPath</background>
      <altBackground>UI/AlternativeBackgrounds/PathBG_Frostshaper</altBackground>
      <tab>Psycasts</tab>
      <tooltip>Frostshapers are psycaster who devoted their life to pursue the cold embrace of frost. This makes them equally as deadly as conflagrators, capable of breathing freezing air and creating localised cold zones that freeze everything in seconds. Frostshapers can also create walls and obstacles out of ice, as well as summon crystals of pure entropy that plunge entire rooms into subzero temperatures.</tooltip>
    </VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
    <VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
      <defName>VPE_Wildspeaker</defName>
      <label>wildspeaker</label>
      <description>Wildspeaker path is a special path locked only for Tribal-based psycasters. It’s all about controlling nature and animals for defense and survival.</description>
      <background>UI/Backgrounds/WildspeakerPath</background>
      <altBackground>UI/AlternativeBackgrounds/PathBG_Wildspeaker</altBackground>
      <tab>Psycasts</tab>
      <tooltip>A secret path of the tribal communities, wildspeaking is the art of living in harmony with the forest and nature, and being able to summon the aid of the forest when needed. Tribal wildspeakers are known to control packs of territorial animals, be protected from all damage by an impenetrable shield, and they can also seem to make brambles and trees sprout out of the ground on a whim.</tooltip>
      <lockedReason>Tribals only</lockedReason>
      <requiredBackstoriesAny>
        <li>
          <categoryName>Tribal</categoryName>
          <slot>Childhood</slot>
        </li>
        <li>
          <categoryName>Tribal</categoryName>
          <slot>Adulthood</slot>
        </li>
      </requiredBackstoriesAny>
    </VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
    <VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
      <defName>VPE_Harmonist</defName>
      <label>harmonist</label>
      <description>Harmonists are all about manipulating the balance of the universe. Their abilities are never a clear benefit or a drawback, and they always come with a price one way or another.</description>
      <background>UI/Backgrounds/HarmonistPath</background>
      <altBackground>UI/AlternativeBackgrounds/PathBG_Harmonist</altBackground>
      <tab>Psycasts</tab>
      <tooltip>Harmonists alter the probability, luck and balance of the universe. They are able to peak under the veil and adjust the scales as they desire, controlling the minds of unsuspecting foes, changing what has happened,influencing what might happen or even overriding the personal history of others.</tooltip>
    </VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
    <VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
      <defName>VPE_Technomancer</defName>
      <label>technomancer</label>
      <description>Technomancers are masters of technology, knowledge and research, capable of using psychic energy to aid in concept exploration, but also to breathe life into small-scale constructs that can help and defend them.</description>
      <background>UI/Backgrounds/TechnomancerPath</background>
      <altBackground>UI/AlternativeBackgrounds/PathBG_Technomancer</altBackground>
      <tab>Psycasts</tab>
      <tooltip>Masters of knowledge and technology, technomancers can improve existing technology, generate infinite power, create constructs out of seemingly worthless materials as well as reverse engineer anything they can get their hands on. Especially powerful technomancers can even use eltex to create psyrings, essentially sharing their knowledge of the psycasting art with other amateur psycasters.</tooltip>
    </VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
    <VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
      <defName>VPE_Nightstalker</defName>
      <label>Nightstalker</label>
      <description>Nightstalkers are warriors of the dark, gaining many combat related benefits when shrouded in the shadows.</description>
      <background>UI/Backgrounds/NightstalkerPath</background>
      <altBackground>UI/AlternativeBackgrounds/PathBG_Nightstalker</altBackground>
      <tab>Psycasts</tab>
      <tooltip>Silent assassins who strike from the shadows, nightstalkers move under the cover of darkness, gaining power from the absence of light. They are capable of skipping to wherever  darkness prevails and executing multiple, near-simultaneous strikes to their target’s heart.</tooltip>
    </VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
    <!-- <VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
      <defName>VPE_Animat</defName>
      <label>animat</label>
      <description>?????</description>
      <background>UI/Backgrounds/AnimatPath</background>
      <tab>Psycasts</tab>
      <lockedReason>Tribals only</lockedReason>
      <requiredBackstoriesAny>
        <li>
          <categoryName>Tribal</categoryName>
          <slot>Childhood</slot>
        </li>
        <li>
          <categoryName>Tribal</categoryName>
          <slot>Adulthood</slot>
        </li>
      </requiredBackstoriesAny>
    </VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef> -->
    <!-- <VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef>
      <defName>VPE_Puppeteer</defName>
      <label>Puppeteer</label>
      <description>Puppeteers Psycasts provide the ways to exploit minds and dominate others. They are the masters of subjugating enemies and creating mindless husks upon which they feed.</description>
      <background>UI/Backgrounds/PuppeteerPath</background>
      <lockedReason>Imperials only</lockedReason>
      <requiredBackstoriesAny>
        <li>
          <categoryName>ImperialCommon</categoryName>
          <slot>Childhood</slot>
        </li>
        <li>
          <categoryName>ImperialCommon</categoryName>
          <slot>Adulthood</slot>
        </li>
        <li>
          <categoryName>ImperialFighter</categoryName>
          <slot>Childhood</slot>
        </li>
        <li>
          <categoryName>ImperialFighter</categoryName>
          <slot>Adulthood</slot>
        </li>
        <li>
          <categoryName>ImperialRoyal</categoryName>
          <slot>Childhood</slot>
        </li>
        <li>
          <categoryName>ImperialRoyal</categoryName>
          <slot>Adulthood</slot>
        </li>
      </requiredBackstoriesAny>
    </VanillaPsycastsExpanded.PsycasterPathDef> -->
</Defs>